# Venanzio Maurizio Petrarolo

89 Pretoria Ave Atholl, Sandton, 2196

Mail: petrarolov@gmail.com

Cell: 072 602 5254

### **Profile**

Currently completing third year of a Bachelor Degree in Chemical Engineering at the University of Pretoria and has a keen interest in gaining work-related experience during scheduled university vacation periods. In particular, would like to take advantage of skills and interest in the following:

- General and analytical problem solving in process engineering
- Innovation and creative thinking processes

As these relate to engineering and management topics.

A highly motivated, goal orientated individual who has past all first and second year subjects with a second year average of 68%.

# **Experience**

## **DISTELL VACATION WORK (DEC 2016–JAN 2017)**

Worked for eight weeks during the vacation at the end of second year in a cider making facility. Was able to gain valuable work experience and exposure to industry during this time. This work involved various investigations, report writing, lab work and general plant work.

## **JOHANNESBURG JUNIOR COUNCIL (2012–2013)**

Served on the Johannesburg Junior Council for the 2012/13 term as a head of committee.

#### **Awards**

# REPUBLIC OF SOUTH AFRICA PRESIDENT'S AWARD (2014)

Gold level President's Award recipient.

#### Skills

Has a code B South African drivers license.

Familiar with chemistry lab equipment and operation.

Has experience in using power tools and equipment such as a drill press, welder, angle grinder.

Programming experience in python.

Competent in the the following programmes: Excel, Word, Powerpoint, OneNote, SolidWorks (CAD software), LT spice (electrical simulations), Photoshop, Pinnacle Studio (video editor) and Audacity (audio editor). Excellent public speaker.

Plays field hockey.

#### **Education**

## HIGH SCHOOL EDUCATION: ST DAVID'S MARIST INANDA (2010-2014)

#### Academics (2014), Matric average of 78%, distinctions shown by \*

Subjects: Mathematics\*, English, Afrikaans, Life Orientation\*, Accounting, Visual Arts, Physical Science, Life science\* (biology), Advanced Programme Mathematics

#### Hockey (2011-2014)

Selected for the St David's First team squad in 2013 and 2014, received half colours for hockey in 2014. Also, Played for Wanderers Hockey club, men's third team.

#### **Debating (2011–2014)**

Was part of the St David's team that won the SACCEE championship in 2013, received half colours for debating in 2013, was elected captain in 2014.

#### Public speaking (2012–2014)

Received half colours for public speaking in 2014.

#### Community service (2012–2014)

Accumulated in excess of 200 community service hours and received full colours for community service as well as an award for school service.

### Leadership (2013-2014)

Received full colours in leadership in 2014; as well as the school's highest accolade—the Marcelen Champangat Medal for excellence in community, service, culture and sports. Also trained and served as a school peer counselor and founded the school filming society.

#### Future problem solving programme (2011–2012)

Represented South Africa in the Future Problem Solving world championship in the USA as the youngest member of the team.

#### Referees

D Petrarolo—Cell: 0828092725—Mail: <a href="mailto:dino.petrarolo@nrgeneration.com">dino.petrarolo@nrgeneration.com</a>

N Bezuidenhout—Cell: 0842030978—Mail: nielbezui@gmail.com